[ Music |
[ cheering and horn honking |.
Oh, Anne.
Oh, hello.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, look at you.
Oh, you haven't changed a bit.
Neither have you. I've been aching to see you.
| know.
Oh, no, don't. Thank you for your help.
Alan? Ha, ha, ha...
Seems like a hundred years since you Sat behind us
in school pulling our pigtails.
Gosh, Anne, don't remind me.
Why is Alan...
Well... why?
He's well-paid, Anne.
| insisted Fred hire a driver,
'cause we have so many guests coming and going.
Spend your money on your family,
Diana, not on me.
You're family, Anne.
Besides, I have to spend the inheritance.
Aunt Jo left me somehow.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
[ clamouring ]
Strange seeing so many young men in uniform.
Look it...
That's Charlie Sloane, and Wilf Bell.
It's like they're running off to a Sunday school picnic.
In six months this nonsense in Europe will be over
and we wont hear another blessed word about war.
Oh, Anne, we're going to have a fabulous holiday together.
Just like old times.
Yes.
Smell the air, Diana.
You find that sweet smell in Halifax.
In your letters you sounded
so happy about teaching in the Hopetown orphanage.
It must have broken your heart to say goodbye
to all your students after five years.
Let's go by Green Gables, Diana.
I've not been back since Marilla died.
Imagine,
sheep on the main street.
The man has no sense at all.
Stop it, Diana, I'm dying
to walk anyway.
No, Anne.
You know Anne, Alan, she's so ridiculously impulsive.
Pull the car around to Green Gables farm, Alan.
She'll just be a moment.
Yes, Ma'am.
Anne, wait... wait, wait.
A-Anne... wait, wait, wait.
I-| broke my heel.
| should have warned you.
Mr. Harrison's really let the place run down.
He rented it out.
Marilla and Matthew would be
heartbroken at this sight.
Hey, watch it.
Get out of the way.
Get back in here! Now!
You two want something?
| was raised in this house.
It was a beautiful home once.
This dump?
You've no respect for the lives that have been lived here.
Do us both a favour, scat.
Anne, Anne.
Let it go.
There's nothing you could have done.
Mr. Harrison's going to get a tongue-lashing
from me when | see him next.
Huh?
Those were Marilla's June lilies.
They were beautiful once.
Leave it.
Ahh!
Go get 'em.
Give me your shoe!
What? No!
Fetch!
My gosh, Anne that worked.
That was my favourite pair of shoes.
[ Laughing } | should have bought this place myself after Marilla died.
| should have taken every penny | earned from my book
and my magazine articles and made this place mine.
Oh, Anne, don't try and rewrite the past.
Now, | want you to forget your troubles.
You'll be very comfortable living with us.
Aunt Josephine's money has left me without a care in the world.
Fred's the youngest manager In the history of the bank.
Isn't that right, darling?
Mm-hmm.
My little inheritance hasn't hurt
his career either, to be sure.
If you call doing nothing a career.
You've managed our business affairs brilliantly, darling.
No, I just mind my own business.
Fred's so modest.
He's turned out to be a wonderful father
and a good husband, Anne.
Sarah.
Yes, Ma'am.
Please take the children upstairs now.
Come give Mommy a kiss good night.
Good night, Mom.
Good night.
Good night, sweetie.
'Night.
Come along then.
They do so prefer their father.
It's such a delicious evening.
Let's have our tea in the garden.
This house is so conducive to writing.
If you stay for the summer,
just think what fabulous ideas you'd compose.
That's a big if.
Diana, | don't...
Feel right intruding on your family.
What's the matter?
We have everything.
But he doesn't even kiss me good night anymore.
I'm sorry.
Well, haven'tyou tried speaking about it?
Oh, Fred was never a big conversationalist,
even when we first got married.
It's a different kind of silence now, though.
He's so preoccupied with the war.
That's the thing about staying engaged...
You and Gil never change.
That's probably because we never see each other.
If you put off your wedding any longer,
you're going to be an old maid, Anne.
Actually...
When Gil finishes his term at Bellevue hospital in August...
August?
How dare you deny me the pleasure of planning your wedding?
Let me finish.
| didn't say we're getting married in August.
We're going to choose a date
oh, Anne, don't be coy.
Oh... You can move back right away.
Anne, life is going to be just the way it was when we were girls.
Sarah! [Anne] - Should we consult Gilbert? [Diana] - Sarah!
Anne and Gil Blythe are getting married!
And it's not going to be some shoddy affair either.
And Fred will help too.
Oh, oh... Please let him.
It'll be a project for the three of us.
Just one thing at at time.
We need to slow down and consult Gilbert too.
No, you let me talk to Gilbert.
We can start with sending him a telegram.
No.
Oh, how I've missed you all summer, Gil.
With perfect memories of days passed.
[Giggles] That'll be fine.
There.
And memory of perfect summer days of old.
Our past, our friends.
[ squealing |.
Are you all right?
[ laughing ]
Nothing broken or bent, | hope.
Ha, ha, only my pride.
Oh, Gil, help me up.
Lam, lam truly blind and a fool to boot.
Oh, if | were blind,
| should never forget the contours of your face.
Why didn't you let me know?
| wanted to see you face to face.
| have something to ask you.
| do.
Let's go take a walk down the lane.
If Diana has her way, we'll be married by the end of the week.
We've been engaged so long,
figure people 'round here think we got married years ago.
Yeah.
What were you going to ask me?
| have a decision to make that may turn our plans upside down.
What?
Bellevue hospital has asked me to remain on staff for the year.
But we agreed that at the end...
Yeah, Anne | realize that...
This is a remarkable opportunity.
| know you've resisted coming to New York in the past...
You're asking me to go with you?
| couldn't bear another year without you.
| want to be with you too, Gil.
Then come with me,
right now and we'll go immediately.
|...l couldn't be happy living anywhere else but here.
This is where | want to be.
So many memories locked up here.
| can't leave it alone.
| wish | could have done something.
This place is in both our souls, Gil.
| wish we could grow old together here.
Come on.
We've still got a few years ahead of us.
I'll go.
What?
To New York, I'll go.
Just to see if | like it first.
But promise me we'll come back to raise our family.
| promise.
New York is an exciting place for a writer.
All the best publishing houses
in the world are there.
Are you sure?
I'm only sure of one thing...
That I'm scandalously in love with you.
Come on, we better tell Diana and Fred,
before they start sending off all the invitations.
[Horns honking]
Well, this is it, Winfield Publishing.
Don't be nervous you'll be fine.
It's unbearable to have insignificance
ingrained into your very soul.
No... Mr. Winfield, he's likely to reject my manuscript
like everyother publisher I've been to this week.
This is a much smaller company,
and | doubt that he'd have brought you in for a meeting just to say no.
'Morning, sir!
I've made up my mind to go to my grave unwept,
unhonoured and unsung.
But not unpublished.
I'd like you to meet my flancee Anne Shirley.
This is Dr. Powell.
An honour, Miss Shirley.
| very much appreciate the opportunity here, sir.
Your book is marvellous.
I've just seen old Winfield. He assures me he'll consider it.
It's the least | can do
for the flancee of our most important young surgeon, uh?
Don't settle for anything less than 10% royalty from the old tyrant.
Excuse me.
| have an appointment to see a Mr. Palmer Winfield.
Name?
Miss Anne Shirley.
There's a Miss Shirley to see Mr. Winfield.
Those stairs to the 6th.
Thank you.
[ knocking ]
Ah, Miss Shirley.
Hello.
- Sit down...
- If you will.
It's a lot of stairs.
How do you do, sir?
Oh, miserably.
Book sales are in a detestable slump.
The overhead of this organization is a can of worms.
This is Mr. Owen
in charge of our fiction department.
Well, thank you both
so much for taking the time to meet with me...
Thank Dr. Powell.
He cut a tumour out of me once,
thereby prolonging my unfortunate existence.
Perhaps we should get down to
the short strokes, hmm, Miss Shirley?
We read the manuscript Dr. Powell submitted.
Lively and engaging, | suppose.
Yes, uh, you have some promise as a writer...
But not here.
| run a business, not a charity.
We've never published stories for young women.
Our specialty is adventure, detective novels and all manner
of books for a man's man.
However, since men are not buying.
SO many books now with the war on,
we really would like to develop women's adventures
wanted to for years
we need someone to apprehend writers and stories
that will appeal to women.
Well | can guarantee you | can smell a good book
before | even open the cover.
Yes, well now,
Mr. Owen is prepared to train you
in the position of a junior editor.
The process of finding material, however, is very subjective.
Oh, | can find writers that women will want to read,
as long as it doesn't preclude me
from submitting my own manuscripts amongst them.
Well, Miss Shirley, they would have to meet our criteria.
And what is that?
I've never published anything | didn't like.
And that's served me well for 40 years.
Oh, you'll like what | find, sir,
as much as you'll grow to have faith in me.
Il find a small corner for Miss Shirley to work in, sir.
Come along, Miss Shirley.
There ought to be a desk
underneath all of that somewhere.
Our research department will find you lists.
Do what you can.
My office is right there.
Miss Shirley... please.
Oh, I'm sorry, | was just taking it all in.
Well, that is a portrait of Jack Garrison Jr.,
America's top mystery raconteur.
A half million copies of his espionage novels guaranteed
before he puts pen to paper.
Now, you'll have to find men who can write that way for women
or you'll be wasting your time.
Mr. Owen, | rarely waste my time.
Besides, if | thought only men could write for women,
| might not find anything interesting.
Hmm, yes, well, | should mention to you
that we have never published a female author...
Ever.
Oh, blast.
Allow me, doctor.
Ah, all right.
Finish up, Gil.
| want you in the board meeting In half an hour.
Certainly, | no longer have the fortitude to continue to serve
this institution, in light of my deteriorating eyesight.
Ah.
This young fellow is the foremost surgeon in his class,
and | might add, in the entire institution.
He's been asked to stay on till the end of the year,
but he has the talent and the stamina to assume my duties
as a permanent member of the administration...
Within the month.
Well Sir, lam very flattered.
| just wish you hadn't launched this
without discussing it with me first.
| needed to know where the board stood.
| can't operate anymore, you know, lad.
The prognosis for glaucoma is abysmal.
You'll want to rise to the occasion
and follow in my footsteps.
Dr. Blythe, Dr. Blythe.
| don't know if you remember my wife.
Of course.
We've been waiting eight hours for anyone to see us.
The admitting nurse should assist you.
Mrs. Tweed, has your baby not turned?
| feel something's not right.
Ok, come on, let's sit down.
Mom, maybe you should walk.
Are you having rapid contractions?
Are you ok?
Mrs. Cunningham, this woman is in labour.
See that she be admitted immediately.
She may require surgery.
You needn't concern yourself with indigent cases.
Let me speak to Dr. Moore in obstetrics.
Oh, | can speak to Moore.
But, sir, |am obligated to this patient
by virtue of having examined her in the clinic a week ago,
at which time | requested that
she be admitted into the hospital.
The delivery may be a footling breach.
If she continues in labour any longer, she may lose the child.
Choose where you use your scalpel.
Remember, we've scheduled Mrs. Hamilton this afternoon.
You just met her husband...
On the board!
| can't let her condition go unsupervised.
We can reschedule Mrs. Hamilton's gall bladder operation.
Excuse me.
Dr. Blythe?
Oh, he can't be disturbed.
Please take a seat in the waiting area, Ma'am.
Mr. Tweed...
Your wife is in Stable condition,
but there was a problem with the baby's cord.
We did everything we could, but I'm afraid it was too late.
Too late... we waited and waited.
I'm so sorry.
You heedless.
Take this man out onto the street.
Now come, come you three.
You call yourself doctors!
What happened, Gil?
Lost the baby.
A word with you, lad.
Get used to this, if you're to spend your lives together.
The woman came to us too late.
She should have been hospitalized a week ago.
Excuse US.
This is part of your lot as a Surgeon.
There's some you can afford to save and some who...
This is a large institution.
- You're what | was 30 years ago, Gil.
- Think!
Think of the potential you have, the lives you should save.
Huh?
Oh, take him home, woman.
Give him a good stiff drink of whiskey.
| feel like we've been walking in circles.
You can't expect life to be normal here, Anne.
| knew that when | agreed to come.
[ sighing |]
That's why | wanted you to promise me
that someday we'd go home to raise our family.
| don't think | can walk anymore
without something to eat, Gil.
I'm sorry.
How about | take you for a fine meal somewhere?
A wiener in a bun would be fine.
You know,
| forgot to ask you how things went for you this morning.
- Two, please.
- Mm-hmm.
They... They offered me an important editorial position.
Doc Powell assured me that they were interested in publishing...
There you go, sir.
Could | have two for me please?
Yes, Ma'am.
You've got to continue your own writing,
not working on someone else's material.
It's all right.
| really want this job.
| intend to have Winfield publish a book of mine
if it's the last thing | do.
Forever and forever.
Always Forever.
Now and Forever.
Forever Into Eternity, by Anne Blythe.
By Anne Shirley.
Forever Into Eternity.
You'll jinx yourself with insipid titles like that,
Miss Shirley.
Don't be embarrassed.
Half the people in this building are writing books
on their lunch hour.
You are...
Aren't you?
Jack Garrison.
Tt's, uh, it's a pleasure to meet you, um...
All Mr. Owen ever talks about is your latest manuscript.
A real page turner according to him.
That's one way of putting it,
seeing he hasn'teven seen it yet.
Will you pass this material on to Mr. Owen?
It's the story outline of my latest book,
according to the terms of my contract.
Certainly.
My lawyer will follow up before | go to draft.
You know | have a few moments,
Why don't you tell me about your story?
Maybe I can help you come up with a decent title.
Well, um
| haven't finished it yet.
| was hoping, if | came up with a really gripping title,
it might twig further ideas.
Oh, no, no, no, you're going about it all topsy-turvy.
You must absolutely always start with a firm premise
and a solid ending.
Well... actually, | do have that.
It's the story of a young teacher.
A missionary... set in the himalayas
who tames the heart of a British Colonel.
Oh, please.
| don't mean to laugh,
but you got better ham in your sandwich.
Well, I've been reading all of your works.
And they tell me they want to find the female bookend to you.
And I'm also condemned as a hack in any literary circle.
Aim much higher creatively, if you want
my opinion, Miss Shirley.
Mr. Garrison's father was the top writer
in the firm for years before he died, Miss Shirley.
Luckily, young Mr. Garrison here has
followed his father's success.
No, true success requires passion and a vision,
not just dollars and cents, Mr. Owen.
Delightful as it has been, Miss Shirley,
| do hope we get to do this again.
Good day.
Good luck.
This is the story outline...
According to the terms of his contract
he said you'll hear from his lawyer shortly.
Yes, I'm sure that | will. Thank you.
Why the long face, Miss Shirley?
Ah, this is very frustrating.
| misplaced something yesterday.
It's nothing really.
Well, you'd better put a smile on.
Mr. Winfield wants you up in his office immediately.
I'll be along in a minute.
Jeez...
[ chuckling ]
Apparently Jack Garrison has taken quite a liking to you,
Miss Shirley.
Don't ask me what sort of antics he's up to now,
but apparently his lawyer has requested that you,
and only you, act as his editor for his new book.
So we'd like you to read the material
and then meet with him to discuss it, hmm?
I've never edited anyone's book other than my own.
Isn't there someone with more experience?
No, not really.
Besides, the material's unpublishable,
at least by this firm.
So we want you to meet with him, humour him,
but by all means, make clear to him in no uncertain terms
that unless he's prepared to deliver us a new adventure plot
instead of this... intellectual, political manifesto,
I'm going to drop him as an author.
Full stop, not another word.
Do we understand each other?
Isn't that rather drastic, sir?
This...
Will clearly articulate Our position.
Are you sure | should be the one delivering this message?
Oh, yes.
Yes, Owen agrees that this is
the best way to keep the situation
cheerful... so, off you go.
And remember,
we want adventure, not art.
Anne, by the way...
Don't you let him lay a finger on you.
We go through this ridiculous dance every year, Miss Shirley.
He believes he's writing the great American classic
or some such nonsense.
Good night.
And you are a valued employee, Miss Shirley.
Could you please ring Mr. Jack Garrison's room?
Tell him that Miss Shirley is here to meet him in the lobby.
Right away, Miss.
Mr. Garrison's room, please.
Hello, Mr. Garrison, there's a Miss Shirley here at the desk... to meet you.
Oh.
Yes, Sir.
As you wish, sir.
Mr. Garrison is, uh, indisposed at the moment.
He wants you to go up and wait.
He'll only be a few more minutes.
I'd prefer to wait here in the lobby.
He said he wasn't coming down.
It's the third floor, suite 308.
[Knocking]
Oh, dear, I've disturbed you, Mr. Garrison.
| was told you were expecting me.
No need to apologize.
It's entirely my fault.
[Coughing]
|, uh, | dozed off.
Why don't you come on inside
and you can give me Winfield's notes,
and your own notes.
Ll wait out here in the hall, sir, while you read the letter.
It would be rude of me, to leave you in the hallway.
Please.
That manipulative old despot.
What were his exact words again?
| heard him say if you didn't deliver another adventure
instead of this political piece, you'd be dropped
by Winfield Publishing, full stop.
I've spent the better part of the bloody advance.
Well, it seems to me that one more book off the top of your head
is better than getting involved in some legal wrangle,
especially if they force you to give back such a large advance.
| just don't have it in me.
One more leads to one more,
leads to one...
This current piece is genius, sir.
But how can they possibly publish a chronicle
on the poverty-stricken of Mexico
living in the wake of Teddy Roosevelt's roughriders?
They can sell a telephone book with my name
and the right cover.
Books are packaged goods to them.
[Music]
Sales are down with the war.
Your reading public is diminishing.
| could make up some excuse for you
if you need more time to reflect.
No, don't go, don't, don't.
| have a proposition for you.
Sit down, please... Sit down..
Mr. Garrison
| haphazardly picked this up yesterday...
When we met.
I'm sorry.
| hope you don't mind, but | read it.
And | have to tell you how often | laughed
and cried.
You make me want to quit writing the junk | write for good.
| was looking everywhere for this.
| was moved despite myself.
Once in a lifetime you meet Someone who you consider
is the kind of...
Creative individual that you wish you...
No.
| wish | could be.
Please, Mr. Garrison.
The compliment is a welcome tonic
for someone who's never received
the kind of success you have.
| suggest you decide what you want to do and get back to me...
Mr. Winfield.
Wait, wait - | haven't finished! Wait!
Miss Shirley, wait!
If you don't listen,
Il jump.
I'll throw myself at your feet.
You're drunk.
Besides, people who do it never talk about it first.
No, don't!
Mr. Garrison, whatever it is,
your book is not a matter of life or death.
If what Winfield wants is the next female best-seller, it's you.
L'd would have to submit it under a pseudonym like...
Let me submit the manuscript under both our names.
You're insane. Goodnight.
'll jump unless you agree.
No, you won't, no, you won't.
No, don't, no, don't, don't!
Anne, you have talent, and | need a book. [Anne]- Mr. Garrison please!
I'll guarantee you it gets published
you let me handle the whole thing with Winfield.
Besides, it's a wonderful book.
It will free me from the final spectre
of the Windfield's once and for all,
and get you the reading public you so richly deserve.
The honour would be entirely mine.
It will take me forever to finish the book... I... I...
That's only my first draft.
Let me be your editor.
And we'll submit it within a month.
All right.
I'll finish this draft and send it to you.
Good night, Mr. Garrison.
I'm in trouble. | need help.
Well, it is probably the most absurd scheme
you've ever attempted.
Thanks for your vote of confidence, Gilbert Blythe.
This chance, is once in a lifetime.
And what successful writer has ever written with a pinch hitter.
All writers have editors.
| gave him my new draft.
What if he doesn't like it?
And now I've been invited to a reception
at his family's estate.
| feel like a lamb being led to the slaughter.
No, don't desert me, please.
Take a deep breath.
Believe in your own ability.
Mrs. Lynde did say | had the nerve of a canal horse.
I'm looking forward to meeting this Garrison phenomenon.
Thank you.
You know, | trot Jack out whenever
| want to attract a crowd.
We've raised $2,000 for my hospital overseas
for war orphans.
If we Americans join the allies at war
with the same kind of enthusiasm,
we'll put an end to the blessed mess.
| understand the book that you and Jack
are collaborating on concerns an orphan.
Yes.
When it's reviewed,
I'd like to host a charity ball for our Manoir,
using the novel as the theme.
Well | can't imagine my book as a setting for a charity fundraiser.
You must be Dr. Blythe.
Mr. Garrison.
How do you do? I've been looking forward to meeting.
The subject of such devotion.
You are fortunate to hold
this young woman's intense esteem and adoration.
A writer is often only married to the art of language.
| predict enormous happiness for you both.
Well, uh, thank you.
Anne.
Aunt Kit, Dr. Blythe is one of the senior staff members at Bellevue.
Oh!
We have a number of guests here involved in fundraising.
I'm sure you'd like to meet.
Miss Shirley and | have a bit of business to complicate things.
My nephew looks quite taken with your flancee.
Well, Anne isn't easily influenced
when it comes to her writing.
| don't think he understands what he's up against.
Well?
It's not awful.
It's just not good enough.
| beg your pardon.
You changed everything that was genuine,
all the innocence.
| don't know what happened, but you better burn this.
Burn this?
Start over.
Im trying to write the way you wanted me to.
I've exhausted myself making this work.
[Scoffs] If you don't want to keep at it, go back and teach.
| can smell when something isn't working.
You wanted to be considered a serious writer.
That's why I'm helping you.
No, that's why I'm helping you.
Anne, you have the gift of human insight.
When | try to do better, | fail miserably.
Stop trying to write a best-seller.
You're the one who suggested this.
| came to you for help, Mr. Garrison.
All right, this entire gambit was a terrible idea.
Either you quit crying about it
or go back to the drawing board.
| got this one! | got that one!
What the heck are you doing?
[ knocking ]
Anne...
[knocking]
Anne, it's Jack.
| know you're in there.
| know my comments were a bit disparaging, | admit.
Thank you.
Harold.
Ah, Mr. Garrison.
I'm certainly looking forward to your next draft.
I'm sorry, Miss Shirley's at lunch.
May | leave a message?
- [Gilbert]
- Jack Garrison's notes seem to be pretty amusing.
You know, no one can tell you how to write.
Jack's not telling me how to write.
He's commenting.
Well, you've been published before.
Why do you need him?
My first book was small
and not widely read.
Don't worry... he's turned out
to be a pretty good coach.
Really.
Oh.
Good night.
Heading back to my place.
This is clearly malignant.
I'd prefer to let him have the use of his limbs
for what little time has left... stitch him back up.
No.
| think we can successfully remove it.
It's highly unlikely.
You can't discontinue
without some benefit to this class.
Put it on record that | have declined to continue
for the safety of the patient.
Dr. Blythe!
Get back in there...
For the sake of the residents in the gallery who aspire to be you.
I'm not about to perform just to enhance the prestige of this institution.
I'm sorry.
Gill.
The politics of this organization are more than | ever bargained for.
I'm sorry.
It doesn't feel right that | should be so excited, then.
| want you to read it.
You're done.
We're submitting it tomorrow.
It's the best of everything you've ever written.
Yes!
Oh!
Are you certain?
So much so that l
have no idea why you're going to allow him to put his name on it alongside yours.
Because | couldn't have done it without him.
And you, too.
Oh.
Can | put my name on it too?
[ laughing ]
What if this is the only chance
| ever have of getting it published?
Don't sell yourself short.
I'm not.
Jack is submitting it tomorrow under both our names.
Ok, | can't stop you.
| just think you deserve a proper credit.
Ah, Miss Shirley, Mr. Winfield would like to see us both.
In his office right away, please.
Send those galleys to the top five distributors, Nellis
and those demonstration covers, as well, please.
What?
Oh, that's the cover of Jack's latest.
It's sensational, isn't it?
The book is a complete departure.
He's written it just for women.
You did well in coercing him.
Mr. Winfield feels we've hit pay dirt on this one.
Mr. Owen,
This is my book.
Oh, and, Nellis, send a personal note from me as senior editor, please.
Thank you very much.
Come along, Miss Shirley.
This is my original work.
This is my...
This is my book.
Now, we'd all like to take credit for a job well done,
but let's not be absurd.
Hmm.
I've asked you both here
at the request of Mr. Garrison and his legal counsel,
Mr. Chambers.
How do you do?
There now.
The finest novel Mr. Garrison ever penned,
don't you agree, Owen?
Sir.
Hmm, however,
Mr. Garrison asserts that he co-wrote it
along with you, Miss Shirley.
Mr. Garrison and | haven't
had the opportunity to re-discuss the credit.
But it is my original work, yes.
Unfortunately co-authorships don't sell.
Your name would denigrate the
promotability of Mr. Garrison's.
In any event,
we want out of this contract.
Jack has nothing else to deliver.
And he has other professional interests he wants to pursue.
| sincerely doubt Miss Shirley's
claim, Sir.
She just hasn't the experience.
Well, since your client is SO anxious to be relieved
of his contract, these provisions
obligate us no further than Jack's credit.
But, Mr. Winfield...| pretty much wrote every word.
Really?
Well, if that's the case, you, my dear, are a terrible opportunist.
| wrote this book.
And don't you dare think of publishing these galleys
or anything else of mine, or I'll see you in court.
He submitted it.
His name goes on it.
Good day, Sir.
Uh, yes, good day to you.
Anne.
You hypocritical swindler.
What?
What did you call this business? Packaged goods?
You're all nothing better than a bunch of pirates!
Bad news: He's going to publish it with only your credit.
Good news: You're out of your contract.
Anne!
Anne, wait! They can't publish it.
| won't allow it. You're making...
A big mistake.
The only mistake | made was seeing stars
in my eyes when | agreed to this charade.
Yes, it was a charade.
| wanted to work with you.
| admire your work.
I'm in love with you.
[ slap |.
There.
If it never gets published,
at least I've preserved some dignity.
| just don't know what to tell you.
Nothing.
| have to ask myself, how could | have been so naive?
Because you're always going off so impulsively,
trying to be somebody other than yourself.
But | love you...
For all your unpredictability.
When | said that I'd get used to it here, | meant it.
| won't let you down.
I'll find something else.
Anne,
you're never going to find another job.
In any publishing company in New York once this gets out.
What is so blessed funny?
Oh, come on, Anne.
This is not the end of the world.
I'm never going to be the renowned physician
they'd like to make of me at Bellevue.
I'm happy being a good doctor.
That's all.
Let's go home.
Really?
Oh!
[ laughing ]
[Music]
Anne, there's Diana.
I'm just going to grab a paper.
Diana!
200 men just signed up today.
Where were you?
Just stepped off the ferry.
You can step right back on it and defend your country
if you're worth your salt.
Fred, good to see you.
| see you were accosted too.
Sign of a coward.
Those dames are trying to incite fellas to enlist.
Where are they taking them?
The old quarantine hospital up the coast has been converted
to a convalescent home for the boys
lucky enough to be sent back.
| should drive up, see if they need a hand.
You're not going anywhere, Gilbert Blythe!
You and your bride and | have business to discuss.
Best to choose your battles with these new-fangled businesswomen, Gil.
Well, will you look at that.
Mr. Harrison's gone and sold the place.
Please go.
Aren't you even the least bit curious?
No, and it is cruel of you to go on and on about it.
[Giggles]
What are you smiling at?
You, you silly goose.
Why?
Gilbert's gone and bought the place for you.
[ screaming |.
With a little help from Fred's bank.
That is the most loving and generous thing
that anyone's ever done for me.
It makes up for every unfulfilled dream
| ever contemplated.
Thank you.
Just let me go in alone, just fora moment.
Ok.
[Remembering] - | think you may be a kindred spirit after all.
I'll try and do anything
and be anything you want
if you'll only keep me, Miss Cuthbert.
If | were very beautiful and had nut-brown hair,
would you keep me?
We might be of some good to her.
Always be your Anne, Anne of Green Gables.
| can drive back and forth until the weather gets bad.
Then I'll board and come home on the weekends.
| won't let you sacrifice your education for me.
You blessed girl.
Ils everything all right?
I'm home now.
This is my house.
Diana said | could stay with them until the wedding.
And that way you can live here.
You won't have to board in town.
Oh, | get to do all the work, | see.
| didn't mean it like that.
Oh, my God.
We did the right thing, didn't we?
Sure, we did.
What Is it?
Nothing.
| was just thinking about Dr. Powell.
My leaving was an awful setback to him.
We did the right thing.
Well, we can't always take the most obvious road in life.
[ Bagpipes playing |
[ Man shouting ]- Our gains have been substantial, ladies and gentlemen!
For every 100 men who stood beside our King at Flanders,
over 200 enemy have fallen.
And if this trend continues.
[ Josie |- Gill.
Moody.
Good to see you.
Josie.
We heard you were setting up an office at Green Gables.
Yes.
But so far no one's shown up for as much as a toothache.
Well, there are more crucial events
abroad that need safekeeping more than Green Gables.
| know that, Josie.
Moody, Josie, how lovely.
Anne.
Isn't it sad how few people our age have stayed in Avonlea?
Yes, everybody's left.
Look at here.
Carmody here has become such a big booming city now.
But it's good to see you're staying.
Well, congratulations are in order.
| hear Diana Barry's having the reception.
Yes, | hope you'll honour us with your presence.
Will you be getting married in uniform, Gil?
Gil's setting up to serve the community here.
And the papers say the war is going to be over in a few weeks.
Well, | suppose it's not your fault
if the American papers never report things accurately.
It's nothing less than a disaster.
My three brothers have left.
| mean, even Pa's gone as a Civilian.
All able-bodied men feel a responsibility to protect our empire.
Able-bodied men are needed at home, too.
Look at Doc Stuart running the convalescent home for casualties.
Gil's volunteering there.
Doc Stuart's near retirement.
No one in this town will be seen by a doctor
not prepared to serve his country.
Josie, Moody.
Well, | can see her tongue has grown by yards since we've been away.
That was practically a threat.
She's always been jealous of you and me.
For heaven's sake.
If the only medical help left are the Doc Stuart's,
this island will need all the help it can muster.
| should pay Doc Stuart a visit.
Whoa!
I'm going to see how much assistance | can be here.
| won't be long.
I've got lots to keep me busy.
Gil.
Do you think it's as bad as they say overseas?
I'm worried a war of this size isn't going to be over in
weeks or months, Anne.
What's at the other end can't be glorious at all.
I'll do everything I can...
For now.
We'd be grateful for even a few hours of your time each week.
My practice isn't very busy yet.
'Morning, Jim.
Look at that.
Jim.
Your brother Harry used to play hockey with me
on the Avonlea Avengers.
| lost track of him.
Uh, Dr. Blythe.
| don't think Harry made tt.
Three weeks on a ship coming home with no care whatsoever.
This one's lucky to be alive...
If the gangrene doesn't get him.
Now let's get a look at those dressings.
There's shrapnel in there that won't let it heal.
We could operate right away
if you have anything to knock him out with.
May!
Let's take Jim inside.
There's not much morphine.
Any supplies that you can track down would be appreciated.
They don't even patch them up before they ship them home.
They'd have a better chance if someone took the time on the battle field.
Yeah.
- [ Diana ]
- Oh! There's the ballroom at the White Sands.
Well, actually, we had something a little different in mind.
Well, what about setting up a beautiful white silk tent in the garden for the reception.
We were thinking...
A simple ceremony on the lawn or in the orchard at Green Gables.
Anne, there's so much more room here for all the guests.
But, Diana, there's nothing wrong
with a quiet home ceremony.
It was just good enough for you and Fred
before you started putting on airs.
| do not put on airs, Mother.
Yes, you do.
Well-Fred,
you're finally home.
Dinner wouldn't keep. | let Agnes leave.
Diana, may | speak with you fora moment?
We're in the middle of planning.
It can't wait.
We need to speak privately.
What's so blessed important that you could be so rude?
The money markets have been a shambles
these past few months because of the war
and the bank's having to consolidate.
They decided to close my branch today.
Well I'm sure they'll transfer you somewhere nearby.
I'm not taking another position.
We're well off.
Perhaps you won't even have to return to work.
Anne, Gil! | want to compare lists to yours.
I'm not going back to work, Diana.
I'm enlisting.
Your family comes before your country.
Fred...
What the devil are you doing here so early in the morning?
We need to speak.
Can you give mea lift in before Anne comes over?
|, uh, worked out a budget to manage the monthly expenses.
All our investments are secure.
Fred, | don't think Diana's going to react as you imagine.
Can't you at least tell her...
Gil,
Diana can't face the reality of being of service to one's country.
This has been going on for months.
| understand.
| really do.
Ok.
Give Diana and the kids a kiss for me.
Tell them I'll be back in a month,
once we've cleaned the Kaiser's clock, eh.
God speed.
Thanks.
Hey, back of the line.
We're first to sign up today.
- [ Woman ]
- This is for those of you who lag behind.
You don't want your kids asking you,
"$0, what did you do in the war, Daddy?"
- [ Solider ]
- Are you a pacifist?
Or are you just yellow?
- [| New recruit ]
- You can recruit aman, nota jellyfish.
Anne, what's taking so darn long?
Don't get your knickers in a knot.
[ humming the wedding march |.
Oh, Anne, you're ravishing.
Who ever would have thought a store-bought dress
would satisfy Diana?
But you were right.
Oh, Diana's veillooks perfect for something borrowed.
How's the dress for length?
| may have to take it up a little,
but it's a perfect fit otherwise.
[ screaming |.
Gilbert Blythe, what are you doing?
It's very bad luck
to see your prospective bride in her wedding dress.
Gil, just wait on the porch
and I'll change.
Into the kitchen.
| just dropped Fred off.
He spoiled it.
That's all there is to it.
We're going to haveto change the entire design of the dress to disguise it.
Dear Mrs. Barry, I've weathered lots of bad luck in my day.
| have to stop him.
But Diana, he'll be on the ferry to the mainland by now.
[ slap |.
What possessed you to help him?
Lam not condoning my involvement.
Diana, Diana, he needed someone to see him off.
He couldn't confront you for fear that
you wouldn't understand his reasons.
He told me to say goodbye to you and the kids.
The past year in New York, this war was just
a headline in the paper - Here...
It's our duty.
You're getting married in a week.
But what's the point if you're just
going to desert your family?
[ sobbing |.
Anne, are you going back home already?
Anne?
You don't need to do this now.
We need to talk.
Anne, please.
| have to do this.
Help me with this.
Anne, Anne, | got it.
Call for help.
Emily, Emily, Green Gables is on fire.
Send the blessed fire wagon.
Anne, Anne, you can't, Anne.
No, no!
| guess providence was looking out for the old place.
- [ Fireman ]
- Alright, Jack.
We're grateful, fellows.
[ Fireman | ...And roll these out.
Old Jerry says that he can replace the windows.
Do the repairs right away.
We can finish restoring when | return.
Marry me now... and let me go.
Everything I've ever loved...
It's taken away.
By the power invested in me,
| declare you Officer and Mrs. Blythe
[ applause |.
Thank you.
It's very sweet of you.
Forgive me for what | said that day.
You've done us all very proud, Gil.
Thank you. Shall we be friends now?
- [ clanking ]
- Your attention, please.
Ladies and gentlemen, a toast.
To the happy couple, huh?
Who... are... about to sacrifice.
Some of the happiest days of their lives...
To defend God and the empire.
Hear, hear.
The happy couple.
Well, somebody's got to avert the gloom of Reverend Morgan.
Let's get the Bride and Groom dancing.
Diana, we've waited five years for this.
Don't rush.
[ Music |.
Yes, and another toast... to Officer Blythe...
And all the god-fearing men who are off to destroy the Hun.
[mumbling |]
Don't step on my notes.
They're part of my sermon.
Oh, dear... Oh my...
[ yelling |]
Sorry, I've ruined the tent it appears.
What do you mean the tent was too tall?
Hello, uh, Madam...
Goodbye.
The postman dropped this notice off, Miss Shirley.
Thank you.
There is a registered package for you at the Charlottetown post office.
Oh, yeah.
Do you make lots of money writing magazine articles, Miss Shirley?
No, nota lot,
but, with tutoring, It's enough to get by.
Ginny, you have five weeks before the exams for Redmond.
I'm terrified to the point of dyspepsia.
Promise me you'll brush up over the holidays.
| haven't had a student of mine pass with less than flying colours yet.
Won't you be there, Miss Shirley?
You don't need me to hold your hand, Ginny.
Your latin and greek may be
at the mercy of providence,
but you shall excel
in all the other arts.
That | have every faith in.
Hello, you have something for me.
There you are.
Thank you.
Oh, as | live and breathe.
The world thinks you're hibernating at the bottom
of a well, Anne dear, | haven't seen you all winter.
Rachel.
Have you heard the news?
No.
Davey Keith's signed up.
Has he?
Trust that bright little devil
to come home driving a tank...
But that's not the worst or the latest.
The Wrights got word.
No.
Fred's gone missing at Vimy Ridge.
Oh, my god.
They think they found six other boys from Carmody, too.
Charlie Sloane, Moody Spurgeon...
Apparently, several of their tags got sent
to government house at Charlottetown.
As it happens, Fred's wasn't among them.
[ sighing |]
He's been listed all the same.
Oh Lord, I'll call on Diana.
To the most faithful, to our glorious dead.
Charles Sloane...
Wilfred Bell...
Moody Spurgeon.
And to those missing in action...
Fred Wright and Alistair Covey...
May their weary souls rest in God
should providence call them, too.
Would you all please turn with me to hymn number 550?
Abide with me.
Fast falls the eventide.
Anne? Anne.
| can't, | can't sit in there and listen helplessly.
Come here.
What you hear from Gil?
All of his letters were sent back.
Oh.
I'm afraid.
Something's happened.
| need to know what.
What can you possibly do?
Go to the last field hospital | have record of.
Search from there.
Through all of France?
They won't let civilians to the front.
| won't stay here and wait for my husband's funeral.
No.
| have to go.
You can do what the rest of us only dream of doing, Anne.
Will you be all right?
We're moving in with Mum next week.
The house sold, then?
It's all right.
We were never happy there anyway.
Come and live at Green Gables till | come back.
I'd feel better knowing you were there.
Oh, Thank you.
Thank you.
[Music]
Germans will eat humble pie for sinking the Lusitania,
now that the Yanks have joined up.
It's about time.
Bar-le-duc next.
We're getting off at that field hospital.
Then we'll catch the next train, meet up at Ypres in the morning.
Why isn't the train stopping?
The town must be under siege.
| have to get off my husband may be stationed at the field hospital.
Stand back! It's far too dangerous.
| have to get off! | have to get off!
Give me your hand!
Here! Reach! Here!
Anne Shirley?
What?
It's a joke,
Close the door! Get back!
Open it!
My husband may be back there, please!
There's nothing left,
even if you could get off!
[ gunfire |.
What happened back there?
When the Jerries started trying to level the town,
British minefields went off everywhere.
Field hospital's about the only thing left standing.
How can | get back?
It's a cesspool.
Not many civilians make it this far.
I'm tracking my husband for months.
If he's there, I've missed my only chance to get off the train.
Life is full of missed opportunities.
Ha... What are you doing here?
I've been working as a war correspondent back and forth
between London and Belgium for a year.
Putting the name Jack Garrison to good use?
Hasn't hurt.
American papers love the sensational.
I'm sure they do.
| gasping |.
What now?
Did we hit something?
The Germans have ambushed the line.
[ speaking German |]
Open the door.
[ screaming |.
What in god's name is going on?
Pipe down... we'll get shot because of you.
Here...
Down in the trench.
Hurry.
We got no choice but hide here till morning.
| must find a way to get back
to the field hospital at Bar-le-duc.
Maybe it's the only safe place, as long as it's been cleared.
Get rid of that uniform.
Why?
Jerries will shoot you on sight, like those poor wretches back there.
They were with the Red Cross.
Red Cross volunteers equals supplies.
Jerries are in worse shape than the Limeys right now.
They'll kill you as soon as they look at you if they think you got morphine.
Colette?
Anne Shirley.
Anne Blythe.
Anne, this is Colette.
Hello.
She doesn't speak English.
Her family's scattered.
| planned on getting them to safety,
but plans changed for worse.
Tu dors maintenant... Cherie, tu dors.
Hank heavens not everything was lost.
How old is the baby?
Barely a year.
| never thought I'd live to see the day I'd thank you,
Jack Garrison.
Colette, pour le bebe... Pour vous.
Here, pour vous.
Pour la manger.
Merci, madame, merci.
Jack.
No, thank you.
Anne, | meant what | said back in New York
| wanted to help you.
Your life has obviously gone In one sweeping direction
and mine in another.
| meant what | said, too.
Mr. Garrison.
[neighing ]
It's aGerman horse to boot.
Maybe we can hitch it to a wagon
and help us get back to the field hospital.
Anne, Anne.
They're blowing up the train back there.
Come back.
You can't be sane, Anne, Anne!
Are you hurt?
That's the train they're blowin' up.
Hell of a way to come up with a story material,
huh, Mrs. Blythe?
We'll hitch the horse to the wagon and move out at dawn.
It's clear, move!
They've broken through, Captain.
They gassed us; They broke through.
Fix your bloody bayonets, Officers.
We have to go help.
No, Anne, wait!
Cover the babe. Anne, wait.
Those fumes are toxic.
Couple of whiffs of this stuff, and you won't get up.
| can't move with them around here any more.
What are you saying?
Il catch up with you at the field hospital.
What?
If | don't show up, if something happens.
Where are you going?
| need you to get Colette and the baby to this address in London.
What are you talking about?
| have an apartment there.
| keep it as an office. It's all paid for.
| can't leave France, while you run off and get yourself a good story.
| wish it were that simple. This war has to end.
And | have my part in it.
Field hospital's down in the valley.
Ho, Sergeant!
Sergeant, General Pershing on that train?
| need to talk to him! Wait, damn it!
American soldiers.
Courage, but nothing upstairs.
Madame Blythe vous protege tous les deux.
She's a good woman.
Non, ca suffit, ca suffit.
Au revolr.
Au revoir, little guy.
Amene-moi avec tol.
Wait! Wait!
You are despicable!
If | ever get my hands on you!
Well he'll live
lf we can find a quiet truck for him that doesn't shake.
Picked up a whole company half an hour ago, Doctor.
No one noticed them missing till the gas attack this morning.
And General Spence has orders that we move to Neuf Chateau
by this afternoon.
We'll never get all casualties in from the field by then.
Well then only bring back those that we have a hope of treating;
not these poor souls that are gone by the time we get them.
If we're overrun, they'll capture this hospital for supplies.
Just give them all a good dose of morphine in the trucks
so they can sleep... my orders stand.
Right.
Dope them up.
I'll be outside.
Doctor will be along soon love.
Dr. Blythe!
Colonel Marshall wants you to head up to the clearing station.
Headquarters has been shelled.
They're up to their eyeballs in fatalities.
You can take this ambulance.
Here let me take.
No, no, no, it's all right.
Please help me.
This woman's exhausted.
It's all right.
My husband might be here, he can help us.
I'll get food.
Excuse me, excuse me.
I'm looking for Dr. Gilbert Blythe.
He's my husband.
Up there, love.
Gill.
Colette.
Please, please, take the baby in the tent, please.
Help me!
No time to spare we're being bombed...
Matron round up all available drivers.
We'll lay her down there.
It's all right Colette, it's ok.
It's all right now, Colette.
It's going to be all right.
[ baby crying |.
Promettez... Promettez...
Promettez-mol... Promettez.
Mon bebe... Promettez.
Promise...| promise.
Garde-le.
| promise.
We need every able-bodied driver, Madam.
If you're Dr. Blythe's wife, you can meet him at the next station.
She's gone.
Step this way, dear.
What about this baby?
Field nurses should look after it.
Follow me.
What about the girl?
Stretcher bearer's duty, dear.
Maps and whatever supplies are in the canteen up front.
[ explosion ]
Get moving.
This place is going to be destroyed.
Cripes, that was close.
Here, let me take him. What's his name?
Dominic.
Thank god you can drive, Miss.
When them shell-shocked stretcher-bearers get behind the wheel, lord.
Avoid mud holes at all costs.
Abigail, you navigate for her.
What will happen to him?
Maybe find a home,
a church in the next town - if it isn't blasted to smithereens.
The field hospital's through there.
Unload these trucks as quickly as possible.
Little tyke's bloody hungry, he is.
Here
looks like he's yours from now on.
I'll get you fed.
I'll try and find some food.
Merci, mon Pere.
Soyez prudente.
C'est un miracle, Le petit quia survi.
Et qu'est devenue la maman?
Elle est morte.
Et vous, mon enfant, D"ou venez-vous?
Ah, Je suis...
Canadienne, Je suis Canadienne.
Ah, Canadienne!
C'est tres bon.
On a beaucoup de Canadiens
ici dans notre village.
Vous cherchez une famille
pour s'occuper De l'enfant, c'est ca?
Oui, ah... s"il vous plait, Watch him.
Garde-le, s'il vous plait, While | help les malades.
Have you seen Dr. Blythe here?
He's supposed to have returned
from the clearing station.
| know they were trying to
evacuate the station when we left.
None of them troops have returned yet.
Oh, I'm so close. | just saw him.
You'll meet up again, love. Calm down.
I'm sorry. I've been searching for months.
Did any of the American troops come here?
Sorry, love... all this noise about yanks joining the war,
and | haven't seen one of them set foot on French soil yet.
| see,
Can | help?
Some of them blokes are in dire pain.
Go slip one of these under their tongues with a little water.
Morphine.
Hello.
Anne?
Anne!
Oh, my lord.
Fred?
It is you.
Fred.
Oh, Fred, we thought we'd lost you.
Not yet.
Oh, gracious providence.
All Avonlea's taken you for dead.
C-can you find someone to treat this?
Yes... yes, of course, of course.
Fred, here.
Here, Fred.
Slip this under your tongue.
Right, all right, I'll come back.
Oh, gracious providence.
Oh, Fred... hang on.
Nurse, nurse, can you get someone to help
clean and disinfect this soldier's wound.
Sorry, dear. Soon as a doctor's free.
All right.
Fred, oh, Fred.
How are my little ones, Anne?
How's Diana?
Everyone was fine, | think.
Uh... I've written to Diana.
I've been travelling around so much, she doesn't know how to...
Fred... I'm prattling on.
They say | can't fight anymore.
C-can you get me home?
Gil can help.
Gil?
| saw him at the field hospital.
He's coming from the clearing station.
All right, Fred.
Is anyone going Back to Bar-le-duc?
There's nothing left.
The Germans completely razed the fleld hospital.
Did you see my husband leave?
| don't know.
Well didn't he leave the clearing station?
Please tell me what happened.
Fred!
Fred?
Oh, my god.
Oh, no, no, no.
Dominic!
Mon Pere!
Father...
Oh, no.
Dominic... Dominic!
[ wailing |]
Here we go, here we go.
Help me, please help me.
| have to get this man loaded on.
I'll help.
I'll help you.
Where's this convoy departing for?
All the way to Boulogne, | think.
| have to get a few of these casualties back to England.
[ Woman ]: This whole town has to keep moving!
Ah, Mrs. Blythe.
We need you over here.
Get that ambulance over here!
Step this way. Hurry now.
Please, My husband didn't get out, did he?
| can't say. Get in please-
we've no time to even think.
No, wait! Wait please! The baby!
Give it up to one of the towns women, please!
[ Driver |: Oh, it's like A state of siege, isn't it?
You can't take the mum away from her baby.
Will you get out of the bloody way, we're trapped!
Any other vehicles from Bar-le-duc?
No, this ts tt.
Everybody else left in the field is either captured or killed.
| have to go to the convoy that's departing for Boulogne.
| have a friend in the truck up ahead. | have to see that he gets out.
Well you just relax. Can't get any worse for him.
[ baby crying |
[| Woman |- Load the men back on.
Can't afford to spend the night in this area. Come on.
Load the men back on!
He needs to be fed.
Can we get some milk?
You help unload.
I'll take him to the infirmary.
[ Soldier J: I've got him.
Right.
W-where's Officer Wright?
He was in your truck.
You want to find somebody, lady?
Get back on the next convoy to the front.
But stop wandering around
when these men are clambering for help.
[ Nurse ]: It's all right, it's all right.
You settle down now.
Let me help you.
Soldier, listen to me.
Look, look at me.
You must listen to me.
Nurse?
Officer Wright?
He's over there, Ma'am.
Doctor
| Know this man.
How can | help him?
Well, | had to amputate the arm to remove the gangrene.
But I've done all that | can do.
See that he's lucky enough to get shipped out.
Fred... Fred?
What's going to happen to me?
I'm going to get you home.
Fred, I'm going to get you home.
| saw their faces when you went missing.
I'm going to get you home to your children.
Can | get him on the next ship out of port?
All right.
Cover him up,
and don't anyone hear him cry.
We're leaving for Paris, 'tilda.
The station at the embassy
needs massive help.
Excuse me?
Can I, can | trouble you further?
Yes.
Can you... can you take this note to the embassy
on the chance that my husband's whereabouts
become known to the red cross?
My man is missing too.
It's all we can do but try.
I'll get you home, Fred.
You'll see your loved ones soon.
You'll be all right, Fred.
Fred.
Here Fred.
Fred here.
This is the first stage of the journey home.
I'll verify this is the place.
You go ahead, Anne.
We'll be fine.
No, we've not seen hide nor hair
of that Garrison chap for months.
He requested that we leave everything as is.
| had my concerns at one point he was a Spy.
He said everything was paid for.
Oh, yes, to the letter.
Always six months In advance.
And we do like those American greenbacks.
Are you a relative, dear?
Oh, heavens no.
I'm Canadian.
| worked with Mr. Garrison in New York.
Not married?
| have a child
and an invalid Officer to support,
if you know of any jobs.
Few jobs these days, with everyone evacuating the city.
We're on tenterhooks for this horror to end.
I'm strong from so much physical work at the front.
And I'm prepared to do any Manual labour,
even here at the hotel.
Well, per...
Only opportunity for women these days
is volunteer work and such at the red cross.
Thank you.
We hope you'll be comfortable.
| can't promise anything, Madame.
Mr. Wright is on a list for the earliest shipment
of vets back to Canada in two months.
Nothing sooner?
Only if you're willing to pay.
She says the children are well.
Not a word about herself.
How is Anne?
Doesn't ask about me.
Oh, Fred.
Let me help.
Fred.
Last thing she told me was how.
She prayed you two would have another chance.
She loves you, Fred.
It's hard being cooped up in here
with you typing like a fiend.
I'm sorry.
| didn't realize | was bothering you.
I'm just trying to get these notes from the front typed up
while they're still fresh in my mind... There.
All these months | wish | had it in me to say goodbye to them.
Maybe | should get out and get some air.
Thank you.
Probably do us both some good.
All right.
Everything's going to be fine, Fred.
I'll get you home.
You'll see your loved ones soon.
If they can bear the sight of me.
Over here, Miss.
Missy!
Where is this Mr. Garrison posted?
He's connected to a General Pershing. That's all 1 know.
We last saw each other At Bar-le-duc.
Well General Pershing is involved right now
in setting up a telephone network across France.
If | were to send a cable to the General?
Well you can only try.
Baby arrived safely in London.
Not everything worked out.
Contact as soon as possible.
Awaiting instructions.
All right, we'll see what we can do.
[ baby crying |.
What's going on?
[ bomb exploding |]
Nothing... But | think they're bombing the city.
The Zeps are coming.
Everyone, down to the basement.
Down to the basement, please.
All the way down To the basement, please.
Everything's under control. All the way down.
Everyone, down to the basement, please.
Down to the basement. That's it, ma'am.
Down to the basement. All the way down.
Thank you, Sir.
Mind your step, love.
| hate this stupid old war.
When can! Go back to sleep?
Soon, soon.
You'll remind him some day
he learned to toddle while london burned.
Ha, ha, wonky little thing.
[ bomb exploding |]
Let me out of here.
Fred... Fred.
You're all right.
You're safe down here.
You're safe. Come on.
Not to worry, everyone.
Good excuse to clear out
this load of old rubbish.
[ baby crying |.
Can | hold him, Madame?
All right.
Your baby's not ill, | hope.
Oh, no, no. He's quite fine now.
Just got a little cough.
[ bomb exploding |]
| only ask because...
My husband... He nearly died at the front from the pneumonia.
He's home on leave soon.
All we can think about's getting back to his people in Canada.
Where in Canada?
Halifax.
Ha, ha, no.
| taught in Halifax for five years. We're from Prince Edward Island,
just off the coast Of Nova Scotia.
My dad used to sing To us about Canada.
[ Singing | So farewell to Nova Scotia, You sea-bound coast
let your mountains dark and dreary be
for when I'm far away on the briny ocean tossed
will you ever give a sigh and a wish for me...
[ Anne reading ]: "Dear Mrs. Blythe:".
"We regret to inform you that the whereabouts of your husband."
"Captain Gilbert Blythe."
"Are currently unknown.'."
"We have reason to believe that the enemy"
"may have captured Captain Blythe."
This, um, what does this, what does this mean?
No one knows conclusively if he's dead.
When a prisoner of war's tags
are returned through the red cross,
the prisoner may have been moved to another camp,
or simply disappeared.
Someone must know where he went.
He's the head of his division.
I'm very sorry, Madame.
Please... He didn't just cease to exist.
[ sighing |]
Under the circumstances,
| don't believe they can claim
the individual as missing in action.
Dr. Blythe, like many other medical personel,
may have been captured and forced to work for the enemy.
He may have come in contact With certain information
that made him a target... We just don't know.
What... In heaven's name?
The Findlays asked us downstairs for tea.
| come back to find this.
Where's Dominic?
With the Findlay's. What's going on, Anne?
| don't know.
How much do you really know
about Jack Garrison... Where is he?
| don't know.
| spoke to the DODDS. They don't seem really concerned.
Someone must be watching us.
Diana hasn't been able to arrange passage.
[ Anne ]: Fred! [ Fred ]: We have to get home.
I'm doing my best.
Just be grateful you're as Safe as you are.
Well, it's possible it may have been a thief, Mrs. Blythe.
But, then again, nothing was stolen.
Uh... has this ever happened before?
No, the room has been sealed for months
at Mr. Garrison's request.
Are you sure couldn't have been Officer Wright?
You have to admit he's been acting awfully erratically.
Thank you for looking after Dominic for me.
It's all right.
We had a lovely afternoon together.
| received some news today about my husband.
| found out he was a P.O.W. in Germany.
What do you mean, "was.'".
No one seems to know what's happened to him.
I'm so sorry.
But | keep thinking...
If he was really dead,
surely | would know that in my heart.
| would feel a terrible... emptiness.
You can understand that?
Can't you, Mrs. Findlay?
Shh... know, | know, Anne.
You mustn't give up hope.
Wh... let go fo me! Ahh!
Shh, shh, shh. It's me. It's Jack.
It's Jack. Don't be frightened.
Are you ok? You ok?
What are you trying to do? Scare me half to death?
| have been waiting and waiting.
This is the only safe place for us to talk.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry it's taken so long.
Colette and | need to meet.
SO we Can make arrangements for the, for...
What?
Colette is dead, Jack.
There was a...
The boy?
He's safe. | tried to contact you.
Where is he?
He's in the apartment.
| can't let anyone know I'm here.
Help me.
Get me into the apartment?
Yes.
Someone broke in to the apartment.
Did you see anyone?
No. Why can't anyone know that you're here?
Who's watching Dominic?
| left him with a friend.
Let's hope it's still here.
Can't you tell me what you're up to?
I'm involved in something very important.
| need to make sure you and Dominic are safe.
| know | can trust you implicitly, Anne.
| want to send him back to Canada.
No, no. Don't do that.
My plans have changed now.
Colette and | weren't married.
But Dominic...
He's my flesh and blood.
It was never my intention to get involved with Colette.
But | did.
And | loved her.
You better hurry.
| should never have encouraged them to come with me.
No, you shouldn't have.
Nor put mein the middle of this.
Look...
I'm involved in American government.
Underground efforts to end the war.
But I'm being followed.
| need you to stay put until | can contact you
with arrangements for Dominic.
| can't stay here indefinitely.
It won't be for that long.
Anne, you can't tell anyone.
You can't tell the neighbours,
You can't tell any guests in the hotel, no one,
no one, that I've been here.
Well where will you go?
| got your last cable through Pershing.
You can eave any messages for me at the embassy.
| got to get out of here.
Did you ever find your husband?
His field unit was captured at Neuf Chateau.
| plan to go back for him.
You never give up, do you?
No.
Promise to take care of my boy if anything happens to me.
What's going to happen to you Jack?
Nothing.
Nothing, for the moment. Just promise me.
| promise.
Thank you.
Come and join us, Anne... You need a solid breakfast
before a long day's job hunt.
I'll be fine.
You've been more than generous.
| insist.
Fade away to nothing, you will.
I'm actually very hungry, thank you.
I'll just grab a sweater for Dominic.
Can | order for you?
Thank you, Fred.
I'm beginning to feel like we're a married couple.
Let's get some food.
Mrs. Blythe?
My name's Fergus Keegan.
I'm editor-in-chief of the London Illustrated Dispatch.
| was hoping to introduce myself.
Jack Garrison used to work for us.
And | was wondering if you'd had contact with him.
No, I'm afraid not.
Are you waiting here to meet him for some reason?
L- No-| knew Jack in New York.
And he's just lent my friend and me his apartment
while we're here in London.
Forgive me... Jack used to feed us reports
concerning events at the front, and he is sorely missed.
We were very successful at selling his stories
to the American papers.
And | was hoping that he would be returning to London.
I'm afraid | can't help you.
Excuse me, but how do you know me?
The hotel manager mentioned that you
were staying in Jack's apartment
and that you were looking for work.
And | may be of some assistance there. You are a writer?
Yes, lam.
I'm not planning on being in London for much longer,
but a job would be very much appreciated.
Yes, well,
| would be only too happy to meet you at my office,
if you're interested, and we can discuss any positions
that might be available at the newspaper.
Here... My card.
Well, thank you very much.
And you will keep us informed if you receive
any more information concerning Jack?
We'd be most obliged.
Good day.
Uh, did Mr. Keegan have anything for you, Mrs. Blythe?
Yes, he gave me his card.
Oh well, he's a good man, Mrs. Blythe.
Mr. Garrison always spoke so highly of him.
Maybe he can help you locate your husband.
They have wire services there
and so many fancy new methods of communication.
Well, thank you for mentioning it | was in need of a job.
How do you know him?
So many journalists have resided here over the years.
It's a close little circle.
Well, thank you again.
Hello. Mr. Fergus Keegan, please.
Thank you.
Mrs. Blythe, |am so glad that you called... Please.
| decided to take you up on your Offer.
But, as | mentioned, I'll only be staying in London
for a little while longer before | return to the front.
Well, we do have a temporary post
that requires prompt placement.
The researcher to our society columnist,
Maude Montrose, has left her position.
Sounds intriguing.
Would it be possible for me to utilize any...
Excuse me.
Wages here are one pound, six shillings a week.
That should be fine.
As | was saying,
| would like to avail myself of
the information bureau and the wire service,
if it's not an imposition, Sir.
I'd happily pay out of my own wages.
No no no, my secretary will be glad to introduce you
to any of the journalists or war correspondents
that come in and out of our wire service bureau.
And, after all, one good turn always deserves another.
Fergus!
You completely forgot to specify typing speed.
The ad is exactly as you requested, my dear.
Maude Montrose,
meet Mrs. Anne Blythe.
Miss Montrose,
my background is
mostly editorial... Winfield Publishing house in New York.
| can type 50 words a minute.
Well, we have an agreement.
Please.
You'll be working as her assistant
but, in reality, you'll be working for me.
Frankly, Mrs. Blythe, we need someone
to keep an eye on Maudie.
She has a large clientele of socialites,
many of whom try to express their own views in her column.
Sometimes her approach to politics
is a tad, um, misguided.
Warning me ahead of time of any sensitive matters
that might crop up in her column
would save us all a great deal of trouble.
Well, we have an agreement.
Oh, please.
| was raised in Manhattan.
You're not going to burden me
with some perfidious, little New York editor.
Now, now.
Don't worry, Mrs. Blythe. She won't bite.
I'll leave you two to get acquainted.
Well, the job is a temporary one, Anne Blythe,
until | can move faster on my feet.
Now let me be frank, darling.
My column is the most widely read
in this boring paper.
I'll do my best.
Any writing to do, I'm happy to oblige.
My one mundane chore here...
Is a sleepy, little column called
"helpful hints for house and home, '
buried in the classifieds.
See what ideas you can dredge up for next week.
Your desk is over there.
| told you | wanted someone who met my criteria.
Oh, | see.
You just have to hire this one, don't you, Fergus?
Why don't you have her cover the Harrington benefit?
Perhaps she'll do the world of good.
Hmm.
Gill.
What is "helpful hints" doing on the cover of this rag?
Selling papers.
Women want to read stories
about other women's contributions to the war effort.
Of course they do.
It was my idea.
Mrs. Blythe has captured the enthusiasm of legions of women
who are starting to protest the war.
Look at this:
"Sacrifice and loss"
"are the burden of women on the homefront."
"Like the officer who struggles throughout the trenches, '"
"there is never a moment of release"
"for the loved ones who wait days and weeks"
"in fear of the report of their impending loss.'."
When could you ever write with such empathy?
Could the French embassy go back
to the Red Cross for more information?
| have a good contact there who could at least
verify the source of your letter.
I'm sorry.
We were to meet at 2:00.
It would be delightful
if you could put the same intensity into my needs.
Where are today's proofs?
Photos?
The guest list?
Published menu?
Looks delicious.
The advance "at home" listing?
Well, you've forgotten the catering "who's who' lists..."
That was to accompany this.
And you've had time to do your little helpful hints.
Who's helping who this week?
You mean my report on British women
assisting at the front.
Well, your report, yes...
Penned by Jack Garrison.
| beg your pardon?
You do know Jack garrison, don't you?
Well, | introduced Jack to Keegan, darling.
I'm sorry about my column ending up on the front page...
If that's what's upsetting you.
A word of advice.
Whatever information Jack is feeding you for that
sleepy little column should be burned.
What information would Jack be feeding me?
| haven't heard from him in weeks.
You let Jack know
that Keegan has been selling his secret codes
to foreign hands for months.
Um, I'm afraid | don't know what you're talking about.
Excuse me.
She thinks you put my column on the front page.
So Jack can feed secret codes and information through me.
Oh, it all seems rather preposterous.
Do you think he's a spy?
L... wouldn't know.
Maude has a rather overwrought imagination
she's typically American in that way.
She might say anything to pretend
that she was in Jack's circle.
It's very sad.
She should stick to what she does best.
She has such a strong following.
But for some people, the other man's grass is always greener.
Thank you so much for coming to see me.
Oh, Mrs. Blythe,
have you ever considered public speaking?
| have to attend a local fundraiser
for the Salvation Army.
And your column has attracted so much attention,
I'm sure that they'd rather hear you than me.
I'd be honoured, Mr. Keegan.
Oh, by the way, how is Jack's little boy?
| should think Jack
must be most anxious to see him.
He's doing very well, thank you.
[ chuckling ]
Oh, Mrs. Blythe, there's a phone call for you.
You can take it on the extension.
Go ahead.
Hello?
Jack, where are you?
No, | can't hear you.
I'll meet you in Paris, then.
No... no, | don't want to keep him here,
| want to send him back to Canada.
It's absolutely The safest.
It won't be long before | can afford the tickets.
I'm working.
For Fergus Keegan at the dispatch.
Fergus Keegan.
In the lobby. Why?
Hello?
| heard from Jack Garrison tonight.
He wants me to stay here till he can
make arrangements to bring Dominic to France.
Don't be insane
the Findlays have arranged passage for all of us.
| know.
But | can't leave until | know what's happened to Gil.
You never saw what | did.
Next time, you may not get out.
Gil wouldn't want you to go back and neither do I.
Look, why don't you sleep in the bed tonight, hmm?
You've got us this far.
| owe my life to you,
but | think it's time we all go home.
We're a thrown-together family, Fred.
Maybe this is it.
Maybe you two are all the family I'll ever know.
But I'm going back to try and find Gil... If | can.
Anne Blythe has skyrocketed to prominence
at our newspaper for her thought-provoking
and heartfelt attempts to reach out
to the female population and get them
to feel something about this war.
Mrs. Anne Blythe.
Good afternoon.
| know you all have loved ones at the front
fulfilling their duties.
My husband too believed he had a duty.
And that makes him just like your husbands, brothers, sons.
They all believe that, even if they sacrifice their lives,
it wouldn't be in vain.
They could die knowing
they had helped end this terrible war.
| have been to the front.
And there is little to be proud of now.
There's no glory.
Only horror, loss and devastation.
Until the women of the British empire stand up
and openly acknowledge the suffering,
this war may never end.
| say enough is enough.
Our duty
is to bring our men home.
You caused quite a stir.
| think Mr. Keegan's of the school
that any publicity Is good publicity.
A group smashed up this office when Keegan allowed
a pro-german piece on the sinking of the Lusitania.
| should use the side door regularly if | were you.
Thanks for the information about the German camps.
British medical personel are often kept in isolation.
Big shortage of doctors.
Perhaps the same thing happened to your husband.
Thank you.
Missing something, Miss Montrose?
| warned you that this position was only temporary, Mrs. Blythe.
|no longer require Your assistance.
Mr. Keegan can employ you if you decide to Stay.
I'll finish my assignment this afternoon.
Clean out my desk.
Mrs. Blythe, there are things going on outside
that we have no control over.
Don't play into Keegan's hands.
| only want to help Jack.
What does this have to do with Jack?
Oh, come now.
He's been springing prisoners, gathering information
before the yanks even stepped into France.
He truly believes that the Americans can end the war.
And so dol.
Jack could expose Keegan as a traitor,
but Jack doesn't want to tip his hand just yet.
Who wrote this?
Jack did.
| managed to alert him... Jack's changed the codes
and he's feeding his information to American papers
through The Gazette.
Anne, | have important news.
Please come in.
Yes, Mr. Keegan?
Sit down.
Maude has left the dispatch.
Would you ever consider taking over her column?
Oh.
She told me she didn't need me any more.
She never mentioned anything about quitting.
Well, that's Maude, always trying to pretend
she has the last word.
We had 10 years together.
It was time.
| very much appreciate the opportunity you've proposed,
but I've made up my mind today that I'm returning
to Canada with my friends.
You're not giving up on your husband surely.
| hear the boys in the office were most helpful.
No, I'm not giving up, but I... | figure if all the rumours
are true, that the war will end soon,
maybe he will be released.
What about Jack's whereabouts... | noticed he had
a piece in The Gazette about the armistice.
He never did contact me.
Thank you again for the opportunity.
I've learned a great deal here.
Yes, I'm sure you have.
Tell me, will you be taking Jack's baby with you?
Yes, | think that would be safest.
Mmm.
Well, good luck, Mrs. Blythe.
We will miss you.
Goodbye.
Thank you, Ma'am. Good day.
Anne, you're finally here.
This is my husband, George.
How do you do, Mrs. Blythe?
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
My wife has spoken of your determination and courage.
Not today, I'm afraid.
He has everything secured
to leave on Tuesday.
Will you join us in the sitting room?
Yes, that would be lovely.
I'll just clean Dominic up
and I'll be right down.
Hello. | missed you today.
Yes...
That's a dirty face.
| gasping |.
I've spoken to Jack.
We need to discuss travel arrangements for Dominic
and for your husband.
Fred.
This is Miss Montrose from the dispatch.
How do you do?
The Findlays wanted to play a game of bridge.
| came up to get the cards.
Would you care to join us downstairs
for a drink, Miss Montrose?
I'm afraid that | can't intrude, Mrs. Blythe.
I'll wait for you outside.
Fred, could you Please take Domenic
fora moment while | see Miss Montrose out?
The Findlays are really hoping you'll be joining us.
Fred, I'll only be a moment.
What do you mean make travel arrangements "for my husband",
where is he?
| haven't much time. We can speak over here.
Why did you leave the paper?
| want to get home to the U.S.
I've had enough of London society.
Where is my husband?
Jack has contacted me and he's explained everything.
He thinks he's found a connection in Germany.
[ Jack |: Maude is a pal.
Bring Dominic to me.
| can get you to your husband.
You could be making this up.
You can't take that chance.
Who are you really?
I'm one of a group of loyal Americans
committed to bringing about peace.
| don't understand.
What do you want from me?
Our efforts require your help.
The Garrisons own a chateau in Belgium.
Kit Garrison, Jack's aunt,
runs a local hospice and orphanage there.
Now, Jack thinks that the war is just about to end.
The child will be perfectly safe there.
And | will obtain the proper papers
for you to travel to Liege.
Kit Garrison has certain valuables
that have to be brought across,
but she's too well-known with the enemy authorities.
Now, these valuables can be used
to buy medical supplies on the black market,
and also assist Jack in bribing
certain important people behind the lines.
Now, if you return with the valuables,
they can be safely carried in...
If?
..Once you're there.
Jack's connections will help you find your husband.
None of us are safe right now.
| Know that.
Well, the train leaves at Noon tomorrow from Portsmouth.
Tomorrow?
You do want to return the boy, don't you?
Yes, of course | do.
W-why do you Think | wouldn't?
Well, when you first came to my Office,
| didn't know what you were up to.
You're a good little poker player.
It's been a lovely visit.
[ Colette |: Mon bebe.
[ Colette |: Promettez-mol.
[ Anne ]: | promise.
You'll be safe.
You seem like you're running away.
I'm going back to France.
There's a chance | can find Gil.
What's wrong, Anne?
Don't tell the DODDS about my leaving. Promise me, Fred.
| promise.
Why are you being so elusive?
What am | going to tell the Findlays?
They bought our tickets.
Driver.
Anne, if you're in some kind of trouble, let us help.
No, it's nothing. Don't worry.
Thank you for being so good to us. I'll never forget you.
Guard him with your life, Fred.
Anne you're talking like we'll never see you again.
You'll see me in a couple...
Anne you can't run off like this.
Mrs. Findlay, take the baby. | don't want him with me here Fred.
Waterloo station, driver.
Hurry, my love.
Oh, look at the soldiers.
[ clamouring ]
Garrison is involved in this, isn't he?
You have no idea the kind of danger you could be walking into.
Please, Fred. Say goodbye and go.
Go!
Mrs. Blythe!
Ha, ha, Mrs. Blythe.
| came to say goodbye.
We must be brief. Keegan may have followed me.
I'm sorry we're unable to travel together.
I'm on my way to New York.
Well, thank you so much for seeing me off.
Officer Wright came to say goodbye too.
I've taken the liberty of switching your tickets to first class, thinking
you might find it more comfortable to travel with the child.
I'm so glad that you haven't changed your mind.
No, | haven't.
But Officer Wright is taking Dominic back to Canada.
Make sure you check your tickets before boarding.
And please give my regards to Mr. Keegan
if you two should meet.
| will.
What was that about?
What's going on?
Oh, come.
Fred, | have no time.
Please, go, before there's any trouble.
And don't ever let him out of your sight. Promise me.
What kind of trouble?
[ Man ]: You just go Straight down there.
Your first left.
[ Maude ]: Here's a locker key for Portsmouth.
Open it once you arrive.
Jack could expose Keegan as a traitor
to British intelligence, but doesn't want to tip his hand.
Don't dare send Dominic to Canada.
Keegan will stop at nothing to protect himself,
even if it means taking Jack's child.
Excuse me, excuse me, please.
Fred...| have to take him.
Anne, what are you doing?
| have to take him with me.
Anne, youre not thinking clearly.
Fred, let him go.
| can't explain. Please forgive me.
Anne.
[ Anne ]: I'm going to miss my train. [ Fred ]: Anne don't do this.
Hold on, son, hold on. Stand back.
Passengers only, please.
Anne!
Excuse me.
Shall | hold your little boy?
Uh, no, thank you.
Portsmouth, Portsmouth.
Newspaper here! Get your newspaper!
Newspaper!
Come and get it!
Newspaper here!
Do you need a hand, Madam?
No.
Come and get your paper! Newspaper!
[ Jack ]|: Don't take a chance on wearing this nun's habit yet.
Wait until you're off the boat in France.
Tickets and directions to the Manoir de Bonne Esperance
in Belgium are enclosed.
I'm trusting you to get my boy back.
[ baby crying |.
Passeport, Madame.
Non, desole. Il est interdit aux femmes de voyager.
All foreigner women must be registered for travel.
No good. Very sorry.
But...
Jeez, those honest-to-god American girls look so great to me.
You know what? These godforsaken uniforms are starting to drive me nuts.
You're telling me.
You know when | came over here | still had my silk stockings?
Yeah | remember that. Yeah.
You remember where it's gone now?
Mud.
Mud and more mud.
Excuse me, | couldn't help but notice you're from stateside.
Are you with the YWCA?
Ha, ha, ha, oh, god...
No.
We're actresses.
We're under contract.
For the boys.
We're heading to the front... The French military
won't let any more women than necessary into the danger zone,
so we're stuck wearing these duds.
| threatened to turn all of France into a danger zone
if they kept us from our duty any longer.
Uh, are you registered to travel across the front?
Actually, we spent the last-what? Eight days stuck in Paris
trying to explain to the government
how come we're exempt from all these bloody rules.
Yeah, we got our registration papers.
Why, where are you going?
I'm going to Brussels, and to Liege,
hopefully, if | can get through.
Why don't you stick with us? We can get you in.
Yeah, we'd love a challenge.
I'm gonna get her a different get-up.
Maybe the Red Cross or Sally Anne.
Uh... no, it's all right, thank you.
Vos permits, s'il vous plait.
Allez-y.
Hey.
Who'd you knock off to get your hands on that get-up?
[ laughing ]
[ Music |
[ Train whistle |]
No, | do imitations.
| dance a little. | tell stories.
You know, like this big baldwin locomotive
pulls up into the shed with 4,000 Yanks.
| jumps up on the platform,
doing a handspring to boot, no less.
"Hey, boys, are we downhearted?" l yells.
And | hear this ear-splitting, "Hell no!"
Ha, ha, | tell you...
It is the biggest show on earth.
This war has got me
hook, line and sinker.
Never knowing which song's your last kind of spurs you on.
| envy you.
What are you talking about?
You're acting your blessed heart out right now.
You bring happiness into people's lives.
Happiness, oh, jeez.
Have another nip there, Sister Anne. Ha, ha
| don't even know who the devil | am any more.
We've all been swept up in some tidal wave...
Keeping on the surface for fear we'll drown.
And you do drown.
You do drown.
Along comes some 19-year-old Jimmy something or other, Huh,
from Tulamassoo, Idaho, to pay a call
and tell you about his latest loves.
Oh, and he vows nobody can hold a candle to you.
Then, psst, gone.
Killed before the same hour the next day.
Sometimes, I, |, | can't stop bawling.
| only manage to keep singing my songs
by looking over their heads and not into their faces.
Yeah, well, she's got a bullet
from every guy she ever fell for.
Yeah, ha, ha... There ain't a blank one in the bunch.
Look, | keep them alive in here.
[ Banging |.
What was that?
Salut.
Vous avez vu... l'enfant?
Dans ce compartiment.
Ah bon.
Anne.
Mesdames.
Allez, passeports.
Allez, allez, vos papiers.
All right, all right, here.
Here, here.
Here... Sorry.
Et le bebe?
C'est un orphelin.
Busch, euh, Busch, euh... C'est un nom allemand ca.
Espion allemand Peut-etre, hein?
German? I'm yankee doodle.
Busch? Can you believe he thinks I'm some kind of German beer.
C'est quoi ca? Imposteur Anglais, hein?
Non.
Hey! What are you doing?
Give me the baby!
Ahh!
Anne, Anne!
Anne...
Hey, what are you doing?
Anne!
Dominic...
Where's Dominic.
| don't know.
They threw Mag in the clink, the jerks.
With her bloody name and these blasted German-coloured uniforms
and your accent, they think we're a bunch of spies.
Spies.
Oh, my lord.
Forget it. The doors are barred.
They're going to do no such thing.
What are you doing?
How fast can you dig?
Come on, come on, dig. Dig faster.
Alright. What are you doing?
| don't know... Not sure yet.
Fill it with coal. Hurry!
Here, here.
Give me your shells.
No, no, not my boys.
Give me your shells. | just want the gunpowder.
You can keep the shells.
Not my boys. All right, all right, here.
Look, at this point, it's their way of saying thanks.
Here.
Got a match?
Yeah. Sure.
And your flask while you're at it.
Oh, jeez... Whiskey doesn't work
unless you're having a good time.
Here.
Ok, ok, stand back.
[ Explosion ]
Elsie, run for the woods.
No, | can't go without Maggie. Don't worry about us.
You just keep on treading water. GO, go, go.
Mais ou va-t-elle avec cet enfant?
Ou allez-vous?
Les autres, par ici!
Vers la gauche, tout le monde.
C'est ca, c'est Ca.
Et c'est bien.
Viens, mon viuex.
Voila, voila.
Comme-ci, comme-ca, voila.
Je cherche une petite soeur, euh, avec bebe.
Je suis desole.
Je ne lai pas vue.
Non, non, je suis desole.
You're sorry.
Arretez... Arretez!
Arretez!
Je cherche le Manoir de Bonne Esperance.
Le chateau de... Madame Kit Garrison.
Oui, on y va au Manor.
Venez, Ma soeur.
Merci, merci.
Quest-ce qui se passe?
Merc.
Anne!
Why didn't you wait at the station?
| gasping |.
Trust you to find your own way.
Let me see your face.
Dominic... My boy.
My boy.
It's all right.
Yeah.
We made it.
| think we made it.
You've done something more important than you can imagine.
You're very brave, Anne.
Very, very brave.
Anne Shirley, my dear, you've never looked saintlier.
And you've brought our Dominic home.
Are... Are we s-safe?
Well, they've killed the animals,
bayonetted the furniture
and poured 200 pots of jam into my grand piano,
but this war is over.
The Kaiser abdicated.
The war's going to end.
And Dominic will be very safe here with Aunt Kit.
Oh, let's get you all inside.
Welcome to one of my father's many extravagances:
an impossibly large chateau in the middle
of no-man's-land for summer holidays.
This is where the children play
after lessons and before bed.
This is Regine and this is Dominic.
Will you take him under your wing?
He's going to stay for a while with us.
He reminds me of Colette.
Thank you.
Anne, you look as if you've been dragged through the mud.
Let someone look after you for a change.
Each of these will save hundreds of lives with medical supplies,
what otherwise be impossible to procure now...
And assist Jack to bring this blessed war to an end.
You needn't worry about this young fellow any more.
He's safe here. Bye-bye.
As long as | live.
Bye.
Wave, Dominic, wave.
| never thought it was going to feel like this...
Giving him up for good.
Don't worry.
You'll see Dominic again.
| kept thinking about Gil,
all the reasons that | came here.
| don't want to go into Germany, if he doesn't exist.
Please, tell me the truth, Jack.
Truth?
Open my bag.
Why?
Open the bag.
Look in the file.
Not that one; The other one.
See the signature?
Where? Where?
What?
Where did you get this?
| sprang a P.O.W. a couple of months ago.
Found a medical certificate in his gear.
A month ago?
Unfortunately, the little group I'm with has its work cut out.
We're assigned to bribe certain German officials into a meeting in France,
so the allies can conclude an armistice.
| have every intention of doing whatever
| can to help you, Anne.
[ Music |.
Move it!
Move! Move it!
Keep going.
Move!
Don't stop! Don't stop keep going.
What?
Go!
The city is under siege.
German troops have walked away from the front with
their coats rotting on their backs.
They're looting because no one could stop them, because they're
afraid not of the allies, but of the communists.
| have a contact in here that can help us.
Come on.
There were no other records of any Canadian or American
Dr. Blythes in any of the hospitals or camps.
Maybe he was moved.
You showed me the paper.
You told me you had contacts.
You let me put your own son in danger.
I'm trying to help legions of others.
Don't you want to be part of this now?
| came here for one reason, and one reason only.
I'm not leaving until | have turned up
every single floorboard to find out
whatever | can about my husband.
We convene at the station at 1600 hours.
If | have to scour every barracks in this city...
I'll Keep on trying.
Do you see him?
In a day these men will be free.
They'll be walking away because these Germans
can't be bothered keeping them.
[ sighing |]
Come on.
British troops are already being released all over the city.
He was here.
His name... His name is here.
It's dated October.
Yes, he was here for several months.
Well, what did she say?
Every day, the Germans brought him here from the camp to work.
Then one day, they took him away.
He never came back.
Where did she say they took him?
Anne, they don't ask questions.
Did she say he was dead?
| need proof.
Do you keep a record of people dying...
Anne, this is anarchy.
There's no authorities here to make out a certificate.
He might have got away.
And if he didn't?
| said something to you along time ago.
| meant It.
We can take Dominic.
We can go back to the U.S. of A.
We can be a family.
The German delegation are to be taken by train
to Lacapelle and meet at the Villa Paques.
Then | will drive them to the chimay.
[ Speaking German |.
Lacapelle road, where they will present themselves.
Hello, my boys!
Hello, boys!
My favourites.
What a gentle bunch.
We're here. They're fighting.
| think we should sing a song.
All right. We're going to sing
a song for you, boys.
After that, Marechal Foch has arranged they be escorted
by security train to a secluded spot in the Compiegne forest.
The isolation should hide them
from any rebel aircraft.
President Wilson wants our unit to be part of the delegation.
[ Singing ] no such...
Hey, what's the matter with you?
Sing the song.
[ Vocalizing |.
Boom-ta-rah-rah-boom-dee-yay
ta-rah-rah-boom-dee-yay
ta-rah-rah-boom-dee-yay.
Ahhh! Look, there she is!
[ laughing ]
You're safe!
You made it.
Oh!
What are you doing here?
We're now the villainous vamping lady spies.
Those French soldiers were so convinced we were Germans,
they shipped us across the border.
Now the Germans are convinced it's over.
So we're having a ball.
We're doing way better, by george.
This place is better than no-man's-land.
Hey, where's the little kid?
Why don't you come and sing a song with us?
Oh, yes.
Come on! You can do it!
No, you can't say no to us.
We won't let you.
[ music]
come on, look into their Faces now, come on.
You know the rules.
(singing) let me call you sweetheart
sing.
(singing) I'm in love with you
don't be shy, Come on.
(singing) let me hear you whisper
(singing) that you love me too
(singing) keep your love light shining
(singing) in your eyes so true
you sing.
Come on, Anne.
(singing) let me
(singing) call you sweetheart
(singing) I'm in love with you
wonderful!
(singing) let me call you sweetheart
(singing) I'm in love with you
(singing) let me be...
[ laughing ]
oh!
Oh, my love.
My love... my love.
Tell me I'm not dreaming.
Officer Blythe.
Gil, you remember Jack Garrison.
He's helped me look for you.
We must move quickly. There's going to be a truce.
Jack and his friends are with allied forces.
They'll get us out very quickly.
We don't have much time.
See what we can do.
My associate and | are to escort
you and your delegation to the eastern front.
| expect you'll find it tough to pick up
where you left off from... especially after
all the inhumanity you've seen.
We'll take it one step ata time.
We'll be fine.
| bribed an attendant
with the watch you gave me, Gil.
It's never been put to better use.
What were you two talking about?
Oh, just what fine men we've met who have sacrificed so much.
Gil...
Jack, will you have some tea?
No.
No, | need to find Saunders.
You know that every day... | would pick
a different memory | had of you,
and | would play it over and over and over again in my mind
until every detail... every hair,
every freckle
every part of you was exactly as | remembered.
You need to rest now.
You want to take the safe road home, Anne.
| think the road with you would
only last so long, Jack.
Without you, I'd never have my son, Anne.
The road | began with Gil
is forever.
I'll never forget what you've done for me.
| have a dream...
We all have unfulfilled dreams.
| gave... up Dominic...
I'll always think of him as Our son.
[ sighing |]
I'm sorry to wake you.
[ gunshot ]
Jack, Jack.
Who did this to you?
You re beautiful.
What's happened?
What goes around comes around with outlaws.
Keegan must be really scared.
Don't move.
Gil, Gil, Gil.
Gill.
Oh, God.
Who did his is going to try get off the train.
Either we get him off this train now,
or he's going to bleed to death.
You're going to be all right.
Whatever happens to me... take care of my son.
Keep holding this, and I'll go for help.
It'll be all right.
No.
What's happening? Ls the town under attack?
No more attacks today, Monsieur, or any other day.
It's all over. C'est fini.
What we've all been praying for.
The armistice was signed at compiegne.
What's all this shooting for, then?
All the old ammunitions.
Ils sont fous. Ils sont fatigues.
| can't believe Jack never lived to see the armistice.
He knew.
Please, help me find Dominic.
Dominic?
What's the matter?
[ sighing |]
Dominic.
Where can he be?
A child just doesn't disappear
into thin air.
You said yourself his aunt was looking after him.
What if something happened to her?
For all we know, they could be
on the way back to New York by now.
Gil, when | was in London,
| made a promise.
| told jack, if anything ever
happened to him, | would
look after his son.
We'll have to do everything in our power to find him, then.
That's my promise to you.
Are you going to tell them when we get back?
I'm ready now, Gil.
Living here this past year with Fred and Diana
has made me realize how much things have changed.
Well, a lawyer promised he'd bring all the papers.
Whoa!
Mrs. Blythe.
What glorious countryside.
Where is he?
He's with the stationmaster.
My wife's worried he won't recognize her.
| have all the documents.
It seems that.
Ms. Garrison suffered heart failure
on her return to New York.
The next of kin have no interest in the boy.
I'd never forget you.
| got you back.
You came back to me.
| love you.
Oh.
What?
Whoa.
Dominic.
You promised you'd bring him home.
Look, oh, this must be Dominic.
Oh, he's beautiful.
It's official. We signed the adoption papers today.
Oh, we have good news.
We looked at a house in town this morning.
| think we've more than overstayed our welcome.
Well, actually...
We're not going to be spending the rest of the year here.
What do you mean?
Gil and | talked about it,
And we decided that we want you and Fred
to keep green gables for good.
I'm going to be taking over Doc Stuart's medical practice
in Glen St. Mary, and we drive over
to look at a new house tomorrow.
Ooh... you can't give this place up.
There isn't anyone who
would appreciate it more than you.
We'll come back to visit.
We want to start over.
Oh.
| don't know what to Say.
Our children will be kindred spirits for life.
Green gables will always be here this way in my heart.
It's never looked so peaceful.
Just the way it was when | first came here as a child.
What do you think, Dominic?
We have to make a new life,
but built on all the old foundations.
We'll build a good home
and raise a family
with lots of scope
for the imagination.
Oh, how | loved it here, Gil.
But green gables will always be a part of me.
Come on gil, let's show him all our old haunts.
(Laughing)